Anto Sebastin Prakash Technical Publications

CONTACT

- +91-9790831225
- 💌 antosebastin98@gmail.coi
- Chennai, Tamil Nadu
- 📊 /in/anto-sebastin-prakash/
- Portfolio

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Advanced Level: CATIA Composer SolidWorks, Corel Draw

Medium Level:
Blender
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe After effects, InDesign
CREO, Team Center

Basic Level: 3DExperience, Photoshop AutoCAD SAP

EDUCATION

2015 - 2019

DMI COLLEGE OF ENGINER

Chennai

Mechanical Engineering (72.

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Tamil (Fluent)

PROFILE

With 5 years of extensive experience in technical publications, I excel in creating 2D illustrations for wallcharts, service manuals, and parts catalogues. Creating 3D animations for dismantling, assembly procedures and inspection steps of vehicles, Skilled in Analyzing, creating and organizing parts catalogue BOMs, Spare parts Lists, I possess strong logical thinking and commitment to continuous learning, driving my passion for excellence and innovation in all my work

KEY SKILLS

- Ability to manage multiple tasks
- Ability to learn new tools quick
- Experience in creating excel templates/macros to simplify works to reduce time and error
- Having self made excel templates for BOM tasks

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Illustrator

Apr 2024 - Present

DICV, Chennai (On the payroll of Insightek global consulting)

- Developed and maintained parts catalogue BOMs and Illustrations of Bharat Benz bus including Engineering changes updation
- Developed Excel templates for BOM related tasks like Reference taking, QC templates, BOM comparison.
- Experienced in tracing images and creating illustrations for service manuals

Parts Author

Jun 2021 – Nov 2023

GGS Information Services, Chennai (Deputed to Ashok Leyland, Chennai)

- Created 2D and 3D parts catalogues using CorelDRAW and CATIA Composer, including BOM analysis and Change updation.
- Developed 2D illustrations for service manuals and wallcharts from 3D models using Adobe Illustrator, InDesign and CATIA Compose
- Produced 3D animations for showing dismantling, assembly and Inspection procedures of Automobile vehicle parts using CATIA Composer
- Developed Excel templates for BOM tasks to reduce errors and time

After Market (Parts Catalogue)

Jan 2020 - Jun 2021

ZF Wabco, Chennai (On the payroll of Randstad India)

- Prepared BOMs and illustrations for parts catalogues of automobile air systems using CREO 4.0.
- Created illustrations for service manuals using PowerPoint.
- · Streamlined processes and managed BOMs using Excel

Design Engineer

May 2019 - Dec 2019

3C Engineering, Kovur

 Designed 3D Models and 2D drawings using SolidWorks & AutoCAD for trolleys, fixtures, and production line components based on customer requirements from free hand sketch